Yesterday, Dr. Will Caster was only human...
Transcendence is a thriller, science fiction,
drama film directed by Wally Pfister.
Two leading computer scientists work toward their goal of Technological Singularity,  as a radical anti-technology organization
fights to prevent them from creating a world where computers can transcend the abilities of the human brain.
Dr. Will Caster, played by Johnny Depp.
Evelyn Caster, played by Rebecca Hall.
Max Waters, played by Paul Bettany.
Agent Donald Buchanan, played by Cillian Murphy.
Bree, played by Kate Mara.
Colonel Stevens, played by Cole Hauser.
Transcendence is a 2014 American science fiction thriller film directed by Wally
Pfister (in his directorial debut) and written by Jack Paglen.
The film stars Johnny Depp, Morgan Freeman, Rebecca Hall, Paul Bettany, Kate Mara, Cillian Murphy and Cole Hauser, and follows a group of
scientists who race to finish an artificial intelligence project while being targeted by a radical anti-technology organization.
Paglen's screenplay was listed on the 2012 edition of The Black List, a
list of popular unproduced screenplays in Hollywood.
Transcendence was a box office flop, grossing just $103 million
against a budget of as much as $150 million.
The film received mainly mixed reviews; it was criticized for its plot structure,
characters and dialogue but praised for its cinematography, acting, and score.
The film explores themes of mind control, artificial intelligence
(a.i.), computer virus, technology, nanotechnology.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and thought_provoking.